hello
and welcome back to another episode of
hermitcraft as you can see i'm still
tagged look at the dunce head on me it
hasn't been too bad actually apart from
the parkour at the start it hasn't
affected me too much and the armor
hasn't even been that bad either as for
the base
i have decided to do a few things so i'm
going to create one more layer this one
here and although i've decided to create
this layer i'm having second thoughts
because this is so small on the top of
here i feel like i need another
not entire layer but just something
around the edge here to make this look a
little less lonely
so i might add that in i'm not sure i
need to make sure i get this right as
you can see
we're approaching the height limit so
even if it goes round i don't i don't
know this is a sort of thing where
freestyling on these kind of builds
isn't good and hello
welcome to america
what is this
we noticed that little pedestal at the
bottom
but what is this
it is the statue of hermitcraft
oh my goodness this is really good and
oh my goodness the amount of blocks this
took
what is this for we gotta go and have a
look at this
convert gems to blank heads confirm oh
my goodness
we can buy
this means we can buy our heads we can
buy our own heads
where am i where am i
there i am
green for sale oh my goodness this is so
cool well we're definitely gonna have to
buy some of these at some point
wait a minute these guys have custom
heads on they're not perfect villagers
oh this is so cool i've actually got
quite a few gems so we could buy a load
of custom heads when we need them not
entirely sure what we need custom heads
for i've got a load of them back in the
base
and also it's come to my attention that
this built mystery building that i don't
quite understand how it works
has a bikini on it it
has a bikini i think that was supposed
to be a bow tie
but i've got to agree
that looks like a bikini
well this building has just lost all of
its respect if you asked me it was like
this it was i think it's a stock
exchange i'm not really sure how this
works
i'm not really sure what this is going
to be or how it works
i'm definitely not going to be trading
in any companies my traveling car is
definitely not going on the stock
exchange that belongs to me forever you
can't really take a building seriously
when it's dressed like that we're going
to do a bit of work to the base today
but there's a few things that i want to
do before we get cracking on the base
because as you know i'm tagged and this
is actually a pretty good opportunity
for me to mess with people
obviously nobody wants to be tagged
right nobody wants to be tagged at all
so i can just scare a few people first
before we even get into anything imagine
i turn up you know because of the dunce
head that i'm it and people are just
gonna run away and panic and it's gonna
be hilarious and then we'll actually
work on getting rid of this there's a
slight problem
i am not allowed to use rockets when
tagging someone i can use them at any
other point in the game to get around
and stuff but i can't use them while i'm
tagging somebody which means i've got to
land or i guess like walk up to them run
up to them which causes a bit of an
issue for me
so
when i'm going to go and scare people i
am going to use my rockets because i'm
not actually going to be tagging them
i'm just scaring them off
i've seen quite a few comments uh lots
of you want me to tag false symmetry who
has not been tagged yet and she's not
even online so i think we should just go
and do a little bit of scaring first
and i think we should start with our
little mustache friend mumbo jumbo leo
who should be somewhere over here
there is the afk man himself
the afk now it's against the rules to
tag anybody afk as we know i could set
up a little redstone afk trap here but
mumbo is not going to be our target for
today
oh he's there
did he literally just no don't you
pretend to be afk he's not scared
he's not he's not scared
he's cornered though oh it would be so
easy to tag him right now
so easy i don't even need rockets i'm
not chasing him
he
he has nowhere to this is so perfect
don't worry
we're bros
i won't tag you
oh whoops he's a little bit he's still a
little bit scared architect bros don't
tag each other unless they really really
deserve it don't worry bro i just i just
came to skate i could tell that it
worked because you were afk and you came
back and you went
[Music]
[Laughter]
well that's one person scared let's see
who else is on we have biffa
or rendog
now rendog was the person that iskaw
wanted me to get
let's see if we can scare him i have no
idea where his base is i have no idea
where anyone's base is really
on this side of the map
is a complete mystery to me i kind of
have an idea oh wait he was working on
this wasn't he this is his station i've
got to say this is probably one of the
best builds in the entire game scars
tree this is for his landscaping
business i think the idea of using these
for rain out oh no this was a bad idea
oh
got out of there that is such a
realistic thing with all the different
colors even the purple ones are kind of
working there
really really nice i love the way this
looks although it's raining on snow
which i don't quite understand but
either way this is so cool and we need
to go and look for someone to tag or
well scare
the hermitcraft server really is coming
together but i can't seem to find
anybody there's only other two other
people here rendog and tinfoil chef and
i have no idea where either of them live
let's just sneak around
i've been here before
i don't see wren's name though
oh ow
what the heck oh really there's another
puffer fish in here
where even is he
busted
busted busted busted right i i don't
really want to remove him because he's
not mine we're going to run through
yep great ow that really hurts so here
is the entrance to rendog's base but it
doesn't seem to be what he's using at
the moment
now ren's gonna be making this meaning
he might need a lot of sand meaning he
might be grinding
out in the community sand area it's the
only other option i can think of because
who knows where tin foil chef is i've
never seen him on this server once
so i have no idea where he is or what
he's up to might be a good good
opportunity let's go and have a look
up to the top of the tower
whoa
the canyon's been demolished absolutely
demolished i did play my part in this
but it's been actually like it's had its
head shaven off
okay do we see anybody
this has been decimated as well hello
is anybody here
well this was my last hope
no idea but there's actually something
else that i wanted to sort of play
around with today now i have spent a
huge amount of time in the trident farm
made by tango
thank you very much tango for letting me
use it and i managed to get myself five
tridents five tridents and i've put
loyalty on all of them i'm going to
demonstrate the concept behind this so
at the moment
if i throw a trident as far away as
possible and i just create and make my
inventory full
it comes back it comes back but it just
flies around me and as you can see it's
just sort of
it's not really flying around me at all
it's just sort of lagging around a bit
so i thought
what if
what if i did this with multiple ones
so this might take a little bit of
ingenuity here because even if i try and
throw them really far away
they come back before i can
throw them all you see that
so i got two are they a two there
i also wondered
can you in theory outrun your trident i
don't know what the loyal like how
strong is this loyalty so let's give it
a go
so it's coming back for me i don't know
where it is but we're gonna see if we
can out oh there it is
all right it came back so while we're in
the air what we can do is throw
a load of these tridents
whether they go down or up i don't know
and then we scarper away
at the speed of sound
and do we see them coming there they are
they're coming back can we outrun them
no we definitely can't can we out
maneuver them why aren't these other
ones coming back hello
tridents oh there's one and number five
number five
trident five
have i lost a truck is it possible to
lose a trident i don't even know where
to go to look for this now
would it be just on the floor somewhere
ah this isn't good
oh it came back
well it seems no matter what they do
come back in the end alright so let's
give this a go
so we're going to throw them up
throw
throw and then
cover ourselves in dirt and they should
in theory make their way back to me
but not be able to get into my inventory
at all well there they there they all
are
oh my goodness
they're freaking out
i am the trident king
they can't quite get they look like
they're impaling me or scratching my
face
and then i have infinite ammo so it's
like i can use them just one after the
other this could be a really clever way
if your inventory is full to just have
like infinite arrows you just have them
all
in limbo flying around i'm pretty sure
they're supposed to spin around you in a
circle but they're just sitting in the
middle of my head i wonder if you could
do this with a lot of tridents and i
mean a lot of tridents there's no way
i'm going to be able to get enough but
imagine you had an inventory full you
managed to fly around throw all of them
and then fill your inventory like i have
how many it would look like hair moving
hair
oh
oh my god actually got him
now if we take back our dirt
we have five tridents again
oh that's brilliant i
i think personally the trident is one of
the best weapons in the game
it's just a shame it doesn't do that
much damage i just wish it did a bit
more some of these have better in chance
than the others like this one this one's
magnificent some of you were wondering
why i called my pickaxe the fax machine
and that's because it's a fast pickaxe
so it's the it's the fast axe the fax
machine it's it's not the most inventive
thing in the world but i just wanted to
call it something everyone else has
named all their gear i haven't yet
oh my goodness false has just got online
we should go and do some recon that's
what we should do recon our recon the
target see what she's working on and
then see if we can do something creative
well she's right there
no no no
oh she's made this portal private
she knows i'm here oh she's scarfed
she's left
she she knows what's up
did she straight up leave oh okay she
might know what we're up to now there
was somebody i heard rockets
it's false i can't use i can't use
rockets to get her right now
we can still scare her though right
[Laughter]
i found him i found him let's see him
panic
[Laughter]
he's panicking he's panicking
he's punching me
[Laughter]
[Music]
he's put his legs but it's a lighter on
oh my goodness i want to tag him so bad
oh it's too easy
it's too easy
i could oh he's totally accepted his
fate
oh everyone is so scared everyone is
freaking out oh my god you could see the
panic
he could see the panic
oh this is so funny you can see him he
jumped around he tried to put on his
elytra
oh this is this is so much fun this is
so much more fun than actually tagging
people just getting the reactions out of
everybody
ren's gonna show me where tinfoil chef's
base is because i have no idea where it
is and i'm having too much fun scaring
everyone oh this is it this this is his
base
there he is
he's down there
rendy ren you can't hear me but he's
down there all right ren's off tim's got
nowhere to go
people really need to like prepare an
escape route
let's see if he reacts he doesn't know
i'm here does he
[Laughter]
the realization
i think they all realize after i haven't
done it
that i'm not gonna tag them
it's so much more funny just to
to pretend to tag people
and now we back out of the room
real slow okay apparently he wasn't
scared but i startled him
well i think that's probably enough
scaring for the time being
that's so funny right we actually need
to go and find a way a clever ish way of
getting false
now that she's been lulled into a false
sense of security that i'm just out to
scare people because she will have been
reading exactly what's been going on in
the chat she might not actually be
expecting me to
actually do it false's base is this
beautiful aqueduct thing that's going on
here with all the purple wool
there we go this must be the entrance to
her base okay
i think my best bet is to create
a secret room above her base and stake
it out okay so this is her base here we
just need to create a one block high
flooring
so
when she comes back
i can just dig through land on top and
tag you're it easy peasy so we just need
to i don't know make this a little bit
more homely while we wait well i don't
think this is happening anytime soon i
don't think she's coming back on
so maybe we'll leave it for today
and hope to get her when she comes back
online next
all right simple as that we're gonna
place an allium right over the top of it
so this lone allium here is gonna be
where our little secret room is i guess
for now
we'll spend our time startling people
and continuing to work on our base
you may also notice that i have
organized a lot of my stuff
i've got well a pretty slick
organization system i was getting so
frustrated with all of the rubbish
around and i'm still not done i mean
i've still got chests full of just junk
junk it's still gonna take me a long
time to put it all in the right place
but i think it's getting there i don't
have as much stuff as i thought i did
and look this is my collection of heads
here i've got phantom heads cod salmon
wither mini guardian drown skeleton
horse this is my collection of heads
here and you also notice that i decided
to put the towers inside the base and
that's because
i actually realized despite it being
maybe a little bit
cumbersome inside here
it it will actually make it a lot easier
for me to decorate it's very difficult
when you're doing interior to decorate
one big room because anything you make
in this large space is gonna excuse me
i'm trying to talk
anything that you build in one large
room is going to stick out like a sore
thumb unless it is also massive so for
example that little concrete maker there
it just looks silly because and it
always will be because it's just a small
thing in a big room
so i decided that i'm gonna put these
towers going all the way through the
building
and
i'm gonna find it a lot easier i think
then to decorate these especially with
this beacon around like i can do some
pretty cool decorations i think
oh my goodness she's back
oh she's back
i knew it if only ah i didn't i didn't
hold out very long if i just stayed in
that room just a little bit longer
it would have been fine now we've
probably got to come in from a high
altitude
to make sure that she doesn't see me
coming at all
nice and high up here
right there's our base
now we don't know exactly where she is
but i know exactly where her base is
so it's right there we're gonna go
straight down
come in for the landing
she's there she's there
i could try and dig really fast down
or she gonna come straight out the front
door
she could come out straight out the
front door
oh this is nerve-wracking she will
suspect something instantly if i try and
mine i didn't think this through
anything that makes a noise is a
giveaway maybe we should stick to the
original plan she's looking through
she's looking through stuff
go for it
oh no the dogs the dogs the dogs the
dogs
it's done
it's done she got tagged she got tagged
yes
the original plan worked oh her
reactions are scary her reactions are so
scary
oh my goodness she hit me with the sword
no no no leave me alone
false i'm so sorry i'm so sorry
i made the mistake of i asked i asked
the subs who was next and your name was
quite free
see i got a couple of warnings as well
and i didn't pay attention to them i was
like there's so many people he could he
could make you pick and
and you went for me
i did i even put you in a full sense of
security by scaring everyone and then
you wouldn't you did he did i was like i
was like oh he must be saving it for
next time perhaps
no yeah you you're close dude my dogs
nearly got you there
your reactions are scary like i dropped
through that roof and you had turned
around with your sword that wasn't in
your hand originally and popped me
that was ridiculous
that must have been just muscle reflex
going
yeah yeah and then i just instantly
right-clicked my dog as well and then
yeah they went for you yeah
it's just so sad it didn't kill you oh
that would have been like the the icing
on the cake it was a little bit close
i'm not gonna lie it was it was quite
close
i know why the cats after me
i don't know there's three of them out
here yes that's crazy
did the cats come after me as well
because they weren't out here before so
i don't know why do cats do that i don't
think so
they just hate
they really love you
they do i think they're they're learning
from the dogs i think do you know do you
now know what you have to do next
i don't actually no this is the first
time i've been tagged you finally got me
okay well you've got to go to the tag
tower and you've got to do the worst
parkour that you'll ever do in your life
and then and then you got to read the
rules and stuff so
you get given a twist so like a bit of
like a set of rules that you've got to
follow so when i tagged i wasn't allowed
to use rockets while tagging which is
why i actually i made a little hidey
hole up here um just above your base
i heard you
i made a little hidey hole here so that
when when you came back on i could just
drop through the roof and i was like
playing darts in here i wasn't very
subtle but i still got you you weren't
expecting it from above i don't think
no i wasn't actually that was that was
pretty good that you died bombed me as
well yeah sure i'll walk you to the tag
tower i feel bad
thanks oh we'll fly
let's say
yeah we'll fly
it's somewhere over here around these
mountains ah you're actually quite close
it is
yeah i'm really close all right so this
this is it this is where
this is where i leave you i guess
because i'm not tagged going upstairs is
for those
those that have been blessed oh is that
where i have to go up yeah i haven't
been up there yet if you don't know
anything you might want to have a quick
read of the book here right i will be
i'm going to have a refresher okay
all right well good luck and let me know
what you get
i want to see what what twist you get
not using rockets was difficult because
it means anyone could just fly away and
that was it i couldn't couldn't chase
after them
yeah yeah
so hopefully it's something easier than
that
and then i know i know some of them that
are in there and that was not one of the
worst
okay okay
well wish me luck ma'am all right good
good luck
oh well we got rid of the dunce head now
we can wear some proper armor again
i'm so glad she was expecting someone to
touch she she completely knew that
someone was around we were very lucky i
think
oh
forces are forced to be reckoned with
that was super scary the the reactions
of that i was very close to dying ah
that means we can crack on with the rest
of today's episode and we can continue
making this build
being
being tagged is both fun and not fun you
get so many limitations but you can
spook people which is not gonna lie it's
a lot of fun
things are really starting to come
together in here and i'm very happy
there's a little bit of an issue though
i've messed up somewhere
just these don't quite add up all the
way around it's just it's not something
here right when we started this entire
project i went wrong somewhere i'm not
entirely sure where but it's gonna take
one of those painstaking hours trying to
work out exactly what block is off and
it might end up being like that one and
that one are wrong or just that one or
maybe three are wrong and one is right i
i just don't know i'm gonna have to sort
of trial and error until i can get it
right
it's almost complete in here but as you
can see it's all very dark and lighting
is gonna be an issue i think we can
however make some decent progress and
just finish this up i've been thinking
quite hard about what i want to put
inside of these towers especially as
they run all the way through the
building they are a sealed location
and if
designed correctly can be pitch black so
at the moment i kind of want them to be
mob farms but i'm not entirely sure how
to make a custom mob farm like this i
might need to employ the help of tango
to design a three-pronged
custom mob farm that's going to produce
lots of drops preferably along the lines
of creepers to be honest so that i can
get my hands on a bit of tnt not to
mention infinite rockets but it doesn't
just have to be mob farms maybe those
two could be mob farms and this one
could be a normal farm maybe i could
drag in some villagers from somewhere
and have an automated farm like these
these are just the perfect size to house
anything that i need whether it's a farm
whether it's a mob drop or elevator or
anything they're a really nice enclosed
space
and that seals that up and as you can
see it instantly goes pitch
black here i need to figure out a way of
lighting this up because at the moment
these torches
these torches suck they are not a cool
way to light this up i need to get
really creative with some lighting
and also this appeared and you're not
gonna believe this tag told me to do
this look at that face look at that face
she's not happy
she got the twist give green a diamond
block i'm so glad we put that back now
that is the ultimate irony i also went
caving for a little bit maybe in here
yeah you can see i've got a few stacks
of iron because i imagine at some point
i'm gonna want to make another beacon so
i thought i might as well start
collecting a bit i don't have an iron
farm and i'm not buying any iron at the
moment
so that's you know long-term goals or
whatever a few hours caving and i got
myself a bunch of stuff and that
actually translated to a stack and a bit
that's not bad at all so i'm thinking
what we do
is
i might make one of these towers full
height to kind of get an idea of what
this might look like because again i'm
freestyling at the moment i'm not
entirely sure what all of this is going
to end up looking like i'm not really
sure what style this is or even if this
counts as a style it's a bit it's a bit
odd i don't think i've ever built
anything quite like it but
normally when you have a vision for
something you can make it work one way
or another and other times it ends up
being a hideous failure we're just gonna
have to see which one this is
this is kind of difficult to explain
from the air but let me try
so my idea is imagine this is tower one
this is tower two
and this is tower three
my idea is that every time you go
inwards you go up a level so as you can
see i've i've leveled that off there and
we're going to go up a bit
this one here is going to be like four
blocks maybe above this one and then the
one at the back is also going to be that
so this is level one and then this one
will be one block higher
then that means this one will be two
blocks higher which means that this one
will be three blocks higher
and it goes round so then this one will
be four blocks higher
and this one will be five blocks higher
as we get gradually closer to the top it
will look like it's circling around
that does look a little bit odd at the
moment because it's not symmetrical and
i'm using just one block but hopefully
that should work on the bigger scale
especially with there's going to be like
another little bit in the middle there
and especially if it makes it to the
full height what i need to know is how
big is that how much space have i got
how many of these i can fit in
i basically just need to do a bit of
math work to work out exactly how this
idea fits into here
and what the actual number of these
blocks going up is
i don't normally mathematically
calculate this especially as this sort
of build has been free form since the
start i haven't really been thinking too
hard about it i sort of had an idea in
my mind and i've just been winging it
ever since but with this final one
especially as it's gonna be quite high
i think i maybe need to think about this
a bit more carefully and the worst part
of it is i genuinely don't know if this
is even going to look good or work or
anything i'm totally in the dark here
i'm learning a lot about futuristic
build design i'm also trying to give it
my own little bit of flair as well so
i think that's where we're going to
leave today's episode because
oh there's there's no way i want to do
math right now not on camera
so that's the end of the episode thank
you very much for watching everyone i
hope you've enjoyed it
and good
bye
oh
just kidding